Guide to Tuli Kupferberg and Sylvia Topp Papers MSS.385
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV. Projects, 1959-2009, undated; 28 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 38 manuscript boxes, 6 flat boxes, 3 hinged-ring binder boxes, 6 oversize folders, 1 flat-file folder; 3 sound discs (vinyl); 2 sound discs (cd); 2 dvd-r disks; 86 sound tape reels; 273 audiocassettes; 2 sound cassettes (
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Danny Schechter [Part 1], 1999-05-26; cuid20805 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0387)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Danny Schechter [Part 2], 1999-05-26; cuid20806 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0388)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Dave McReynolds, Prez Campaign, 2000-11-01; cuid20807 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0328)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- David Amram, LES [Part 3], 2002-04-03; cuid20808 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0379)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- David Amram's Vibrations, 2001-06-27; cuid20809 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0357)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Dialectics Bertell Ollman [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20810 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0057)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Diane Spodarek Show, 2001-12-26; cuid20811 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0372)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Ed Sanders 65th Birthday [Part 1], 2006-02-21; cuid20812 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0501)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Ed Sanders 65th Birthday [Part 2], 2006-03-07; cuid20813 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0502)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Ed Sanders and Tuli Kupferberg, Bowery Poetry Club [Part 1], 2005-08-26; cuid20814 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0010)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Ed Sanders and Tuli Kupferberg, Bowery Poetry Club [Part 2], 2005-08-26; cuid20815 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0011)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election, 2008-05-19; cuid20816 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0566)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20817 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0214)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election '98, 2000-11-29; cuid20818 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0330)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election Night Folly '96 at the Brecht Forum [Part 1], 1996; cuid20819 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0220)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election Night Folly '96 at the Brecht Forum [Part 2], 1996; cuid20820 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0221)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Election Night Folly '96 at the Brecht Forum [Part 3], 1996; cuid20821 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0222)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Eric Drooker and Flood [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20822 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0408)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Eric Drooker and Flood [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20823 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0411)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Eric Drooker at ABC NORIO [Part 1], 1996-09-22; cuid20824 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0463)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Eric Drooker at ABC NORIO [Part 2], 1996-09-29; cuid20825 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0445)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Eric Drooker at ABC NORIO [Part 3], 1996-10-06; cuid20826 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0464)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Fugs History, Ed and Tuli [Part 1], 2005-12-27; cuid20827 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0457)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Fugs History, Ed and Tuli [Part 2], 2006-01-10; cuid20828 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0498)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Fugs History, Ed and Tuli [Part 3], 2006-01-24; cuid20829 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0499)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Gringo in Mañanaland [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20830 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0188)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Gringo in Mañanaland [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20831 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0189)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Howard Zinn on the History of Freedom of Speech in America [Part 1], 1996-10-27; cuid20832 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0228)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Howard Zinn on the History of Freedom of Speech in America [Part 2], 1996-11-10; cuid20833 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0233)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Howl Poetry Festival [Part 1], 2004-03-30; cuid20834 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0438)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Howl Poetry Festival [Part 2], 2004-04-13; cuid20835 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0439)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Howl Poetry Festival, Allen Ginsberg Tompkins Square Park [Part 1], 2003-10-29; cuid20836 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0420)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Israel, 2009-06-26; cuid20837 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0577)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Izzy Young [Part 1], 1997-02-16; cuid20838 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0413)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Izzy Young [Part 2], 1997-02-23; cuid20839 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0447)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Izzy Young [Part 3], 1997-03-02; cuid20840 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0448)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Izzy Young [Part 4], 1997-03-09; cuid20841 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0449)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Jeff and Jack, BlueStocking, 2006-06-03; cuid20842 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0017)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Jeff Lewis, Helen Schreiner Shop, Cake, 2007-06-04; cuid20843 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0541)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Judith Malina, Poetry Reading [Part 1], 2002-03-06; cuid20844 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0440)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Judith Malina, Poetry Reading [Part 2], 2002-03-20; cuid20845 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0441)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Lenni Brenner [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20846 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0277)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Lenni Brenner [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20847 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0278)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Liedown Comedy of Tuli the K, circa 1996-2007; cuid20848 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0267)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Linc Picks, 2008-04-03; cuid20849 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0563)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Living Theater [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20850 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0087)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Living Theater [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20851 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0088)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Loisaida Fest, Jeff Lewis, Richie Heisler, Paul Thornton, 2006-05-28; cuid20852 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0014)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Loudon Wainwright [Part 1], 2008-11-17; cuid20853 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0579)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Loudon Wainwright [Part 2], 2008-12-01; cuid20854 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0580)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Loudon Wainwright [Part 3], 2008-12-15; cuid20855 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0581)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Music and Madness, 1998-02-04; cuid20856 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0257)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- New Movement and "Violence", Dave McReynolds, 2000-11-15; cuid20857 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0329)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- New Years at St. Marks Poetry Project [Part 1], 1999; cuid20858 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0255)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Nobody for President, circa 1996-2007; cuid20859 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0015)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- On the Media [Part 1], 2007-02-26; cuid20860 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0534)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasong [Part 1], 2007-04-30; cuid20861 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0008)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasong [Part 1], 2007-05-07; cuid20862 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0539)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasong [Part 2], 2007-04-30; cuid20863 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0009)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasongs [Part 1], 2007-03-12; cuid20864 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0535)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasongs [Part 2], 2007-03-26; cuid20865 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0536)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Parasongs [Part 2], 2007-05-21; cuid20866 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0540)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Penny Arcade [Part 1], 2001-07-11; cuid20867 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0353)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Penny Arcade [Part 2], 2001-07-25; cuid20868 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0354)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Penny/Galact, 2002-02-02; cuid20869 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0376)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Pete Stampfel and Jeff Lewis [Part 1], 2008-01-14; cuid20870 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0557)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Pete Stampfel and Jeff Lewis [Part 2], 2008-01-28; cuid20871 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0558)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Peter L. Wilson, Europe [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20872 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0247)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Peter L. Wilson, U.S. [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20873 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0246)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Peter L. Wilson, World Issues [Part 3], circa 1996-2007; cuid20874 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0249)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- PoPro [Part 1], 2009-02-09; cuid20875 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0582)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- PoPro [Part 2], 2009-02-23; cuid20876 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0593)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- PoPro [Part 3], 2009-03-09; cuid20877 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0594)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Punk, 2007-01-01; cuid20878 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0530)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Republican National Convention [Part 1], 2001-10-12; cuid20879 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0451)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Republican National Convention [Part 2], 2001-10-12; cuid20880 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0452)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Republican National Convention [Part 3], 2004-10-26; cuid20881 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0453)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Republican National Convention [Part 4], 2004-11-09; cuid20882 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0454)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sander Hicks and Culture of the Left [Part 1], 2000-05-31; cuid20883 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0317)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sander Hicks and Culture of the Left [Part 2], 2000-06-14; cuid20884 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0318)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sander Hicks and Culture of the Left [Part 3], 2000-06-28; cuid20885 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0319)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sander Hicks and Culture of the Left [Part 4], 2000-07-12; cuid20886 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0320)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Serbian War [Part 1], circa 1996-2007; cuid20887 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0288)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Serbian War [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20888 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0289)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sermon and Song [Part 2], circa 1996-2007; cuid20889 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0269)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Shimmy, Knitting Factory, 2000-07-27; cuid20890 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0323)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Socialist Scholar's Conference [Part 1], 1996-06-09; cuid20891 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0193)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Socialist Scholar's Conference [Part 2], 1996-06-23; cuid20892 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0194)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Socialist Scholar's Conference [Part 3], 1996-07-07; cuid20893 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0195)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Socialist Scholar's Conference [Part 4], 1996; cuid20894 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0196)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Sparrow Poetry, 2002-01-09; cuid20895 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0373)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's 2004 New Year's [Part 1], 2004-01-21; cuid20896 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0426)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's 2004 New Year's [Part 2], 2004-02-04; cuid20897 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0427)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's 2004 New Year's [Part 3], 2004-02-18; cuid20898 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0428)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's 2004 New Year's [Part 4], 2004-03-03; cuid20899 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0429)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's 2004 New Year's [Part 5], 2004-03-17; cuid20900 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0430)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's Poetry, 1999; cuid20901 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0474)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- St. Mark's Poetry, 1999; cuid20902 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0309)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Steven Ben Israel - A Séance to Contact The Living, circa 1996-2007; cuid20903 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0262)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Stolen Lives Project, circa 1996-2007; cuid20904 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0301)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- The Fugs at Woodstock '99 [Part 1], 1999; cuid20905 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0299)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- The Fugs at Woodstock '99 [Part 2], 1999; cuid20906 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0300)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- The Fugs Live at Byrdcliff [Part 1], 1999-09-15; cuid20907 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0302)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- The Fugs Live at Byrdcliff [Part 2], 1999-09-29; cuid20908 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0303)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- The Poetry of John S. Hall, 1996-11-17; cuid20909 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0396)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- TNC LES Fest, Penny and Tuli [Part 2], 1999; cuid20910 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0401)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- TNC LES Fest, Penny [Part 1], 1999; cuid20911 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0400)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- TNC LES Fest, Stephan Smith [Part 3], 2004-01-07; cuid20912 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0425)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- TNC LES Fest, Tuli + Steve Ben, 2003-07-09; cuid20913 (Box 313, Cassette MNN 0412)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Fire Memorial, 2007-03-26; cuid20914 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0012)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Fire Memorial, 2007-04-23; cuid20915 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0538)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tsaura Litzky, 2000-03-04; cuid20916 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0259)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli and Jeff Lewis Interview [Part 2], 2006-06-08; cuid20917 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0608)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli + Judson [Part 1], 1999-04-20; cuid20918 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0312)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli + Judson [Part 2], 1999-04-20; cuid20919 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0313)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli and Jeff, 2006-03-20; cuid20920 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0019)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli and Lanny, 2002-09-28; cuid20921 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0018)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli Channels Marx, 2009-01-26; cuid20922 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0001)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli LES Festival and Joe Franklin [Part 1], 2000; cuid20923 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0358)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli LES Festival and Joe Franklin [Part 2], 2000; cuid20924 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0366)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli on Media, circa 1996-2007; cuid20925 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0004)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Tuli, Perv, 2007-12-31; cuid20926 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0576)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Volcano - Krassner, 1993-11; cuid20927 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0000)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Warhol/Lenny Bruce YouTube, 2008; cuid20928 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0013)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- When the Mode of Music Changes, 2003-02-06; cuid20929 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0016)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Woodstock 2004, cuid20930 (Box 304, Cassette MNN 0002)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- You're Insane, History of the Constitution, Sermon and Song, NY NY, circa 1996-2007; cuid20931 (Box 312, Cassette MNN 0287)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Zinn 30's and 60's [Part 1], 1996; cuid20932 (Box 311, Cassette MNN 0202)
  - Revolting News Television Show -- Other Videos, 1992-2009, undated (Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 317, Box 204, Box 207)
  - Revolting Theater, 1960s-1980s, undated (Box 179, Folder 2-18, Box 180, Folder 1-12, Box 181, Folder 1-9, Box 147, Folder 7, Flat-file-folder 4, Box 210, Box 326, Folder 2)
  - Revolting Theater -- Video, 1995 (Box 316, Box 204)
  - Royalty Statements and Contracts, 1967-1970 (Box 181, Folder 10)
  - RPI Slide Show, 1994 (Box 181, Folder 11)
  - Shimmy Disc Contracts, 1998 (Box 181, Folder 12)
  - Show Notes, Setlists, Appearance Schedules, etc., 1982-2005 (Box 181, Folder 13-16, Box 182, Folder 1-5)
  - Show Songs, Poems, Notes, undated (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Smoking Show -- Notes, 1993-1998, undated (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Song Show, undated (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Sound Recordings on 3" and 5" Audio Reels, 1960s, undated (Box 204)
  - Sound Recordings on 7" Audio Reel, 1965-1966, 1986, 1994, undated (Box 208)
  - Sound Recordings on Cassette, 1978-2003, undated (Box 199, Box 200, Box 201, Box 202, Box 203)
  - Sound Recordings on Digital Audio Tape, undated (Box 203)
  - Sound Recordings on Disc, 1989-1990 (Box 205)
  - Sound Recordings on Disc (CD), 1966, 1989 (Box 205)
  - St. Mark's -- New Year's, 2002, 2003, undated (Box 182, Folder 9-10)
  - Street 1959 -- Materials Found on NYC Streets; 1st Show; 2nd Show (Box 182, Folder 11-13)
  - Tamiment Library Show, 2004 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Tamizdat -- The Plastic People of the Universe (Event), at Irving Plaza, 1998 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Teach Yourself Fucking, 1992, undated (Box 183, Folder 3-5)
  - Theater for the New City -- Lower East Side, 2003 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Theater of the Real -- Videos, 1989-1991 (Box 317)
  - Times Change Press Agreements, Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Tonic, 2000 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Top of the Village Gate, 1988-1990 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - Tour -- British and Dutch Brochures, circa 1992 (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - Tuli and Friends Album, 1965-1992, undated (Box 183, Folder 11-14)
  - Tuli Kupferberg Referenced in Amazon.com, 2006 (Box 183, Folder 15)
  - Tuli Kupferberg Referenced in Media, 2004-2006 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Tuli Kupferberg Videos on Youtube.com, 2008 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - Tuli Show Reserve, circa 1993 (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Unbearables Show at St. Mark's Church, 1999 (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - Unbearables Show -- Trashing Self-Help Books, 1997 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Unicef African Famine Relief Benefit, 1984 (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - The Vagabond's Codebook, 1972-1975 (Box 184, Folder 7-13, Box 185, Folder 1-3)
  - Video Recordings on 16mm Film Reel -- Good Soldier, circa 1964 (Box 203)
  - Video Recordings on DVD-R Disc, 2006, undated (Box 205)
  - Video Recordings on Mini Video Cassette, 2008 (Box 203)
  - Village Voice -- Tales of Kupferberg, 1971 (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Voulez-Vous Coucher Avec God?, 1972, 2007 (Box 185, Folder 5, Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Weatherlove Playbill, 1980 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - WFMU Benefit, undated (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - Woodstock, 2004 (Box 185, Folder 8)
  - W.R. Mysteries of the Organism (Wilhelm Reich), circa 1999 (Box 185, Folder 9)
- Series V. Birth Press/Vanity Press, 1874, 1890, 1948-2008, undated; 1950-1985; 16.50 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 2 flat boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes, 2 flat-file folders
  Arranged in alphabetical order by publication title, followed by correspondence files, which are arranged chronologically. Original, notated folders for Book of Perverbs were retained with the folder contents and placed in acid-free folders.
  This series contains material generated by Birth Press (sometimes referred to as Vanity Press), a small publishing company started in the 1950s by Tuli Kupferberg and Sylvia Topp, in which publications were assembled in their apartment, then distributed to local bookstores or sold on the street. The 50+ works published over the years through Birth Press were a collaborative effort, with Kupferberg as primary writer and Topp as editor and designer. This series contains working files for these works, including edited manuscripts; source material; photographs/illustrations; and layout plates/negatives. Many of their publications, including their ï¬rst title, Birth featured works by Allen Ginsberg, Diane Di Prima, LeRoi Jones, and others in and around the Beat scene, as well as the ï¬rst published work of Ted Joans. This series also contains a notable collection of original children's drawings and writings, as well as general research, gathered for use in their magazine Swing, as well as in their books, As They Were (1973), and As They Were Too (1979). Layout pages, photographs, correspondence, and planning files for First Glance: Childhood Creations of the Famous can also be found in this series. Correspondence related to Birth Press from the 1950s through the late 1990s illustrates the personalities of their readership and popularity of their publications within their lower-Manhattan neighborhood, as well as on a national and international level, seen in the volume of comments and requests for subscriptions and individual publications found in these files. The correspondence files also include submissions and interactions with writers/contributors for publications Birth, Swing, and Yeah.
  Separated Materials
  Birth Press publications were separated from this series and cataloged separately.
  - 1001 Ways to Beat the Draft, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 1001 Ways to Live Without Working, 1961-1964 (Box 28, Folder 2, Box 38, Folder 1)
  - 1001 Ways to Make Love - German Advertisement for Book, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - 30000... Beatniks or The War Against the Beats, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Are These Our Children?, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 33, Box 40, Folder 1)
  - As They Were, 1957-1993, undated (Box 28, Folder 4-16, Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - Beating - Birth Baby No. 1, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Birth #1, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 18-20, Box 35, Folder 1-4)
  - Birth #2, circa 1959 (Box 28, Folder 21-28, Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Birth #3, 1958-1960, undated (Box 28, Folder 29-32, Box 29, Folder 1-28, Box 36, Folder 1-3, Box 37, Folder 8)
  - The Book of Perverbs According to Tuli, 2006-2008, undated (Box 29, Folder 29-32, Box 30, Folder 1-11)
  - The Book of the Body, 1959, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 12-13)
  - Children as Authors: Birth Bibliography #1, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 14-17)
  - Crazy Paper #1 & #2, 1974, undated (Box 30, Folder 18-20, Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Cry, 1948,1953, undated (Box 30, Folder 21-24)
  - Don't Make Trouble, circa 1990 (Box 38, Folder 5, Flat-file-folder 2)
  - The End of 1978, 1973-1980 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Famous People Thoughts and Poems, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - The Grace and Beauty of the Human Form, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 4, Box 37, Folder 10)
  - In Media's Feces, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Kill For Peace Again, circa 1987 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Less Newspoems, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 28, Box 37, Folder 3-5)
  - List of Birth Press Publications, 1961-1962, undated (Box 30, Folder 29, Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Listen to the Mockingbird, 1973-1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 30-31, Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - Panic Pamphlet #1: Rub-Ya-Out of Omore Diem, 1962, undated (Box 30, Folder 32, Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Panic Pamphlet #2: The Mississippi (A Study of the White Race), 1962 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Pedantic Pamphlet #3: The Christine Keeler Colouring Book and Cautionary Tale, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 34, Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Questionable Cartoons, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Radical Humor, 1962-1987 (Box 30, Folder 35-36, Box 31, Folder 1-6)
  - Revbroad 3: New York Times List, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Selected Fruits and Nuts, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 7, Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Snow Job, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Swing #1, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 9-10, Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Swing #2, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
  - Swing #3, circa 1961 (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
  - Swing #4, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 15-16, Box 37, Folder 11)